<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-04T13:45:44+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lcbc12’s bookmark</title><subtitle>To keep an eye on my project updates!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Non Fungible Tokens</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/21/Non-Fungible-Tokens.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Non Fungible Tokens" /><published>2022-01-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/21/Non-Fungible-Tokens</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/21/Non-Fungible-Tokens.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="why-nft">Why NFT</h2>

<p>Since 2021, NFT are becoming more and more omnipresent, almost every blockchain project deals with them.
Browsing through them you can find games, tokenomics, art, etc.</p>

<p>With such an emergence, I could not pass by without being interested in it.</p>

<p>This is why I started this project: to train myself on this technology and see the potential to be drawn from it.</p>

<h2 id="versions">Versions</h2>

<p>I imposed a batch of features on myself through versions to be able to deliver a finished and functional product each time.
So, once a version is finished, I start the features of the next one.</p>

<h2 id="version-1">Version 1</h2>

<p>Version state: <span class="finished">Finished</span></p>

<p>This version was the start of the project, so I wanted to make the very basis about NFT on a blockchain technology that I know well.</p>

<p>For the back-end part, I will use Ganache with Truffle for solidity development.
For the front-end part, I will use ReactJS, connected to MetaMask to sign every transaction.</p>

<p>Here is the diagram of this solution:
<img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Lcbc12/NFT/abc6aa8aad6a60519c74a4cea84eb188d905cc41/NFT.svg" alt="NFT Solution diagram" /></p>

<p>The main objective was to make the basics features: mint and view.</p>

<p>Thanks to this solution, anybody can mint a new NFT, store the metadata generated in <a href="&quot;https://nft.storage/&quot;">NFT Storage</a> and saving the metadata URI in the blockchain.</p>

<p>The viewer will then retrieve all the metadata URI from the blockchain, load it and load the image into the site.</p>

<p>To sum up:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Mint an image, metadata’s URI is stored in the blockchain, metadata is stored in NFT.Storage;</li>
  <li>View a NFT by recovering the image by doing the reverse process.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="version-2">Version 2</h2>

<p>Project state: <span class="not_started">Not started yet</span></p>

<p>For the second version, I want the site to become a marketplace where anybody can sell/buy any NFT she possesses.</p>

<p>I think that I’ll have to work with token economics, not only account.transfer(value) in solidity.</p>

<p>I will try to make the site connect to other cryptowallet and, hence, other blockchain.</p>

<p>To sum up:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Marketplace to sell/buy NFT with other tokens;</li>
  <li>Connection to other cryptowallets.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working on NFT: minting, viewing and transfering]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Proof of Retrievability</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/21/Proof-of-Retrievability.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Proof of Retrievability" /><published>2022-01-21T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/21/Proof%20of-Retrievability</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/21/Proof-of-Retrievability.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="quick-introduction-to-proof-of-retrievability">Quick introduction to Proof of Retrievability</h2>

<p>Because data is becoming more personal and is taking more storage space, it is quite usual now to load a file in Google Drive, OneDrive from Microsoft, etc.</p>

<p>Maybe, some of this data is important for you and you want a way to make sure that data is truly stored.</p>

<p>Unless you want to download entierely this data everyday, there is no solution for you to check if it’s stored.</p>

<p>Or maybe there is in fact one way: Proof of Retrievability.</p>

<p>To sum up, it’s a cryptographic tool enabling a user to mathematically challenge a server to check that its file is still stored.</p>

<p>It works in a five-step protocol involving three parties:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Client: the one that possesses the file;</li>
  <li>Server: the one that has a lot of free storage space to rent;</li>
  <li>Other: other user of the network.</li>
</ul>

<p>The steps are:</p>

<ol>
  <li>Initialization: Client generates some metadatas to start the process;</li>
  <li>Signature: Client signs its original file, making a new signature file. Client sends both files (original and signature) to Server;</li>
  <li>Challenge: Client sends a challenge to the Server;</li>
  <li>Proof: Server computes a proof according to the challenge, the original file and the signature file;</li>
  <li>Verification: Other or Client verify that the proof is correct regarding metadatas and challenge.</li>
</ol>

<p>That’s it! The proof is way lighter than the file and easy to verify!</p>

<h2 id="work-done">Work done</h2>

<p>With the blockchain emergence, Proof of Retrievability found a place in this system.</p>

<p>Indeed, it just needs a smart contract that handle the verification step and here we go, we have a trusted system and a full protocol to store our file!</p>

<p>That’s why I worked with ISAE Supaéro on it and creates <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/2001.07016.pdf">BlockHouse</a>.</p>

<p>I am currently continuing this work with ISAE Supaéro and improving this protocol.</p>

<p>You can find a small part in the Github repository.</p>

<h2 id="versions">Versions</h2>

<h3 id="version-1">Version 1</h3>

<p>Version state: <span class="finished">Finished</span></p>

<p>The main idea is to make the public Compact Proof of Retrievability work.
You can find it here: <a href="https://link.springer.com/content/pdf/10.1007/978-3-540-89255-7_7.pdf">Compact Proofs of Retrievability</a></p>

<p>The smart contract stores all the require metadatas to verify proof, the challenges and the proofs.</p>

<p>A little test script is implemented to verify the protocol.</p>

<p>To sum up:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Public Compact Proof of Retrievability protocol in smart contract;</li>
  <li>Test script to check if it works.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="version-2">Version 2</h3>

<p>Version state: <span class="pending">Pending</span></p>

<p>There, I want to share a tool made from <a href="https://github.com/scipr-lab/libff">libff library</a> to make all the steps describe above.</p>

<p>Then, anybody in a blockchain network with this solution will be able to run entirely this protocol.</p>

<p>I want to add benchmark tool in order to optimize the signing step. Indeed, signing a file generates new elements (to store aswell), so the lighter the better, otherwise this solution requires more storage space than at the start.</p>

<p>To sum up:</p>

<ul>
  <li>C++ tool to sign file, generate challenge, compute proofs and, incidentally, verify the proof;</li>
  <li>Benchmark tool to optimize the signing step and display the protocol performances.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="version-3">Version 3</h3>

<p>Version state: <span class="not_started">Not started yet</span></p>

<p>Once everything is done with the protocol by itself, I want to make a marketplace where any account can propose some storage space, or a file to store with the possibility to check there reliability.</p>

<p>Payment will be made thanks to tokens, not only ether transfers.</p>

<p>I will create a site to display all propositions and a way to make challenges easier.</p>

<p>To sum up:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Marketplace smart contract handling all PoR protocols;</li>
  <li>Website that displays the marketplace and facilitate usage of every protocol;</li>
  <li>Payment by tokens.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Working on PoR: specifically public Compact Proof of Retrievability]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Completing this site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/19/Completing-this-site.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Completing this site" /><published>2022-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/19/Completing%20this%20site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/19/Completing-this-site.html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="filling-project-part">Filling project part</h2>

<p>I’m currently working on two big projects.</p>

<p>For each project, I want to share:</p>

<ul>
  <li>why am I working on it;</li>
  <li>which part is stimulating for me;</li>
  <li>where the development is;</li>
  <li>and where I want it to be.</li>
</ul>

<p>Of course, I want to make as readable as possible with diagram and pictures.
I want to share these projects firstly for people who are interested in the idea, not the code by itself.</p>

<h2 id="filling-blog-part">Filling blog part</h2>

<p>To be honest, I don’t know with what I’ll fill this part. But I’m pretty sure that I’ll need this part soon.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I want to complete this site with my current projects]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creating this site</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/19/Creating-this-site.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creating this site" /><published>2022-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2022-01-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2022/01/19/Creating%20this%20site</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2022/01/19/Creating-this-site.html"><![CDATA[<p>I want to particularly thank Johnathan Detchart for his help before, during and after my launch as a freelancer.</p>

<p>If you are able to browse this site, it’s 100% thanks to him, I just followed the tuto.</p>

<p>In short, I worked with him at ISAE Supaéro and he’s a great person and a very good developer.</p>

<p>This blog will contain every article I find interesting for possible projects and updates for my own projects of course.</p>

<p>Stay tuned if you want to know more!</p>]]></content><author><name>Lcbc12</name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I want to particularly thank Johnathan Detchart for his help before, during and after my launch as a freelancer.]]></summary></entry></feed>